Guide to the Angiola Churchill Papers MC.282
New York University Archives
Angiola Churchill Papers
1972-2016
New York University Archives
Churchill, Angiola R.
MC.282
4 linear feet in 4 record cartons and 2 manuscript boxes
13 videocassettes
Angiola Churchill was the head of New York University's Department of Arts and Art Professions from 1975 to 2005 and the founder and director of the New York University Studio Art Program in Venice, Italy from 1974 to 2006. She also served as the Co-Director of New York University's International Center for Advanced Studies in Art (ICASA). She has a Doctorate of Education and is a practicing artist. The Angiola Churchill Papers document the student work and syllabi of the Studio Art Program in Venice from 1986 to 2002, and the work of the ICASA from 1978 to 1994, in office, marketing, and design competition documents and videos.
Scope and Contents
The Angiola Churchill papers consist of syllabi, photographs and documentation of student works from the New York University Studio Art program in Venice Italy from 1986 to 2002. Also included in this compilation are International Center for Advanced Studies in Art (ICASA) office, marketing, and design competition documents from 1978 to 1994. Slides, photographs, and video recordings from the studio art program accompany the Angiola Churchill papers.
Biographical Note
Angiola Churchill was the head of New York University's Department of Arts and Art Professions from 1975 to 2005 and the founder and director of the New York University Studio Art Program in Venice, Italy from 1974 to 2006. She also served as the Co-Director of New York University's International Center for Advanced Studies in Art (ICASA). She has a Doctorate of Education and is a practicing artist.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
Conditions Governing Access
Material pertaining to individual student records may be restricted in accordance with the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA). Please contact the Archives with specific questions regarding access to such records.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Angiola Churchill in April 2018. The accession number associated with this gift is 2018.068.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact university-archives@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Art -- Study and teaching (Higher); Video art.; Color photographs.; New York University. Department of Art and Art Professions; New York University. International Center for Advanced Studies in Art; New York University -- Faculty -- Women
- NYU Venice, 1994-2002 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
- Report, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Venice, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Lists of Venice Students, Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Venice Program Reviews, Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Venice Reports, Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Venice, 2002-2009 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Venice Information Packet, 1988-1997 (Box 1, Folder 9-18)
- Venice Photographs, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- General Venice, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Video + Lacarno + Venice, Undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Trips Groups, 1995-1998 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Publications, 1980-2016 (Box 2, Folder 1-4)
- Venerezia, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Publications, 1984-2006 (Box 2, Folder 6-7)
- Pallazo Grassi, 1972-1982 (Box 2, Folder 8-9)
- Prof. Churchill, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Venice Palazzo Pemma, 1986-1993 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Venice Tolentini, Undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Video Art Summer 1993, 1 videocassette (Box 3, Cassette MC_282.0001)
- Works in Progress, 1987-1994; 1 videocassette (Box 3, Cassette MC_282.0002)
- N.Y.U. Video Art in Venice, 1996; 1 videocassette (Box 5, Cassette MC_828.0003)
- Video Art - Summer, 1993; 1 videocassette (Box 5, Cassette MC_282.0004)
- N.Y.U. Video Arte a Venezia, 1994; 1 videocassette (Box 3, Cassette MC_282.0005)
- Works in Progress, 1982-1986; 1 videocassette (Box 5, Cassette MC_282.0006)
- NTSC 6403, Undated; 1 videocassette (Box 3, Cassette MC_282.0007)
- Video Prize-Winners Venice, 1986-1992; 1 videocassette (Box 3, Cassette MC_282.0008)
- NYU in Venice, 1995; 1 videocassette (Box 3, Cassette MC_282.0009)
- Venice 1996, 1 videocassette (Box 3, Cassette MC_282.0010)
- Video 99, 1999; 1 videocassette (Box 3, Cassette MC_282.0011)
- Install Video Side, Tempo UQuido, 1986-1990; 1 videocassette (Box 3, Cassette MC_282.0012)
- Hertzig, Reddington, Bullard, Undated; 1 videocassette (Box 5, Cassette MC_282.0013)
- Slides, Undated (Box 5)
- ICASA Design Competition, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- ICASA Venice, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- ICASA Office and Press, 1978-1994 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- ICASA Jorge Glusberg, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- ICASA, 1979-1997 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- ICASA in Venice The Guggenheim, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- ICASA, 1981-1989 (Box 4, Folder 7-9)
- Jorge Glusberg, 1980-2013 (Box 4, Folder 10)